A Guide to the Virginia Train Collectors Association records, 1976-2018
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Virginia Train Collectors Association records, 1976-2018
Library of Virginia
53579
12 cubic feet (16 boxes).
Virginia Train Collectors Association
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the Virginia Train Collectors Association
Historical Information
Virginia Train Collectors Association was founded to provide a forum for the exchange of ideas and articles relating to the collecting, study, operation, and preservation of tinplate trains.
Scope and Content
Records, 1976-2018, of the Virginia Train Collectors Association (VTCA) containing by-laws, membership lists and rosters, magazines, and newsletters documenting the organization, history, and activities of the association and its interests in tinplate model trains. Includes club car models issued annually to members of the association.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged
Series I: By-laws and membership directories, lists, and rosters, 1976-2018
Series II: The Observation magazine, 1980-2006
Series III: Newsletters, 1977-2018
Series IV: Club cars
Contents List
- By-laws and membership directories, lists, and rosters, 1976-2018 (Box 1)
  Contains by-laws for the Virginia Train Collectors Association (VTCA) as well as membership lists, rosters, and directories.
  - By-laws, 1976-1994, no date (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Charter members roster (1976), compiled 2001, updated 2004 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Membership rosters, 1977-1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Membership rosters, 1982-1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Membership rosters, 1986, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Membership rosters, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Membership rosters, 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Membership roster and by-laws, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Membership roster and by-laws, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Membership roster and by-laws, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Membership rosters, additions, corrections, and deletions, 2000, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Membership roster and by-laws, roster additions and deletions, 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Membership roster and by-laws, roster additions and deletions, 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Membershp roster and by-laws, roster additions and deletions, 2007-2008 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Membership roster, additions and deletions, 2009-2010 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Membership roster, additions and deletions, 2011-2012 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Membership roster, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Membership roster, 2015 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Membership roster, 2018 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Blank membership applications (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Membership brochures (Box 1, Folder 21)
- The Observation Magazine, 1980-2006 (Box 1-2)
  Consists of issues of the magazine The Observation which contains articles about the organization and about train collecting.
  - The Observation, volume 1, number 1, December 1980 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - The Observation, volume 2, number 1, December 1981 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - The Observation, volume 3, number 1, December 1982 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - The Observation, volume 3 [4], December 1983 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - The Observation, volume 5, December 1984 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - The Observation, volume 6, December 1985 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - The Observation, volume 7, December 1986 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - The Observation, volume 8, December 1987 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - The Observation, volume 9, December 1988 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - The Observation, volume 10, December 1989 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - The Observation, volume 11, December 1990 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - The Observation, volume 12, December 1991 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - The Observation, volume 13, December 1992 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - The Observation, volume 14, December 1993 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - The Observation, volume 15, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - The Observation, volume 16, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - The Observation, volume 17, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - The Observation, volume 18, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - The Observation, volume 19, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - The Observation, volume 20, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - The Observation, volume 21, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - The Observation, volume 22, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - The Observation, volume 23, 2005-2006 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Newsletters, 1977-2018 (Box 2-7)
  Contain newsletters with information on the organization, its finances, and its meeting dates, as well as mailings regarding train meets throughout the state, picnics and parties, and other information.
  - Newsletters, (volume 1), 1977 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Newsletters, volume 2, numbers 1-5 (no number 6 published), 1978 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Newsletters, volume 2, numbers 7-11, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Newsletters, volume 3, numbers 1-5, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Newsletters, volume 3, numbers 6-9, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Newsletters, volume 4, numbers 1-5 [6], 1980 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Newsletters, volume 4, numbers 6-11, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Newsletters, volume 5, numbers 1-6, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Newsletters, volume 5, numbers 7-11, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Newsletters, volume 6, numbers 1-5, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, volume 6, numbers 6-11, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, volume 7, numbers 1-5, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, volume 7, numbers 6-11, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, volume 8, numbers 1-5, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Newsletters, volume 8, numbers 6-11, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Newsletters, volume 9, numbers 1-5, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Newsletters, volume 9, numbers 6-11, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Newsletters, volume 10, numbers 1-5, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Newsletters, volume 10, numbers 6-11, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Newsletters, volume 11, numbers 1-5, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Newsletters, volume 11, numbers 6-11, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Newsletters, volume 12, numbers 1-5, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, volume 12, numbers 6-11, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, volume 13, numbers 1-4, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, volume 13, numbers 5-11, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, volume 14, numbers 1-6, 199 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Newsletters, volume 14, numbers 7-12, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Newsletters, volume 15, numbers 1-5, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Newsletters, volume 15, numbers 6-11, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Newsletters, volume 16, numbers 1-6, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Newsletters, volume 16, numbers 7-12, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Newsletters, volume 17, numbers 1-5, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Newsletters, volume 17, numbers 6-11, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Newsletters, volume 18, numbers 1-6 [5], 1994 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Newsletters, volume 18, numbers 6-11, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Newsletters, volume 19, numbers 1-5, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, [volume 19], June-December, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, [volume 20], January-May, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, [volume 20], June-December, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, [volume 21], January-July, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Newsletters, [volume 21], numbers August-December, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Newsletters, [volume 22], January-May, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Newsletters, [volume 22], June-December, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Newsletters, [volume 23], January-June, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Newsletters, [volume 23], July-December, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Newsletters, [volume 24], January-June, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Newsletters, [volume 24], July-December, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Newsletters, volume 24 [25], numbers 1-5, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Newsletters, volume 24 [25], numbers 6-11, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Newsletters, volume 25 [26], numbers 1-5, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, volume 25 [26], numbers 6-11, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, volume 26 [27], numbers 1-5, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, volume 26 [27], numbers 6-11, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, volume 27 [28], numbers 1-5, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Newsletters, volume 27 [28], numbers 6-11, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Newsletters, volume 28 [29], numbers 1-5, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Newsletters, volume 28 [29], numbers 6-11, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Newsletters, volume 29 [30], numbers 1-5, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Newsletters, volume 29 [30], numbers 6-11, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Newsletters, volume 30 [31], numbers 1-5, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Newsletters, volume 30 [31], numbers 6-11, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Newsletters, volume 31 [32], numbers 1-5, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Newsletters, volume 31 [32], numbers 6-11, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Newsletters, volume 32 [33], numbers 1-6, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Newsletters, volume 32 [33], numbers 7-11, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Newsletters, volume 33 [34], numbers 1-6, and Thomas [the Tank Engine] Comes to America, chapters 1-3, 2010 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, volume 33 [34], numbers 7-11, and Thomas [the Tank Engine] Comes to America, chapters 4-8, epilogue, 2010 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, volume 34 [35], numbers 1-6, 2011 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, volume 34 [35], numbers 7-11, 2011 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, volume 35 [36], numbers 1-6, 2012 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Newsletters, volume 35 [36], numbers 7-11, 2012 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Newsletters, volume 36 [37], numbers 1-5, 2013 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Newsletters, volume 36 [37], numbers 6-11, 2013 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Newsletters, volume 37 [38], numbers 1-5, 2014 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Newsletters, volume 37 [38], numbers 6-11, 2014 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Newsletters, volume 38 [39], numbers 1-6, 2015 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Newsletters, volume 38 [39], numbers 7-11, 2015 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Newsletters, volume 39 [40], numbers 1-6, 2016 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Newsletters, volume 39 [40], numbers 7-11, 2016 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Newsletters, volume 40 [41], numbers 1-6, 2017 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Newsletters, volume 40 [41], numbers 7-11, 2017 (Box 7, Folder 16)